James Kavanaugh

✓ ikay@northslopesoftware.com

J 253-209-9718

in linkedin.com/in/jkav3

github.com/dangerginger

Software Engineer

Skilled, bilingual software engineer and proven leader with twenty years of experience leading high-performance, crossfunctional teams on mission critical projects. Team builder and master trainer with experience organizing and leading talented individuals. Dependable team player practiced in clear and concise written and verbal communication.

Projects

- Marine Construction Permitting System: Typescript and React client relationship management (CRM) application with AWS EC2 websocket server backend for real-time synchronization with MongoDB NoSQL database.
- Optimal Request for Quote: Typescript and React enterprise resource planning (ERP) application with cloudnative AWS backend to streamline vendor quotes and purchasing for construction companies.
- Vilya Web Socket Framework: Typescript and Node.js web socket framework with message schema validation.
- **Brometheus**: Computer vision application using C++, OpenCV and Tensorflow models to monitor local camera streams, with associated macOS and tvOS client applications intended for home security camera monitoring.
- Space Time: Native iOS and watchOS application with AWS Amplify and RDS backend to help users visualize time according to atomic time instead of as a cycle.

Experience

President and CEO (Owner)

North Slope Software

2022-2024

- Sold, designed, and implemented a client relationship management system for a marine construction company.
- Responsible for business development, user experience design, software development, and DevOps.
- Incepted, designed, and built an enterprise resource planning software-as-a-service (SaaS) product.

U.S. Army Special Forces "Green Berets"

1st Special Forces Group (Airborne)

2004-2024

Indo-Pacfic Regional Program Manager

Washington and overseas; 2020-2024 (3.5 years)

- Led a multifunctional staff to manage joint special operations teams in seven Asian countries.
- Mentored and developed leaders and technicians on high-performing teams to achieve strategic objectives.
- Responsible for written communication and briefings to synchronize operations with senior leaders' intent.

Special Forces Operations Sergeant (18Z) Washington and overseas; 2018-2020 (2.5 years)

- Managed a high-performance, multifunctional, and highly specialized special forces detachment.
- Responsible for training, mentorship, and professional development for a Special Forces operational detachment.

Special Forces Intelligence Sergeant (18F) Washington and overseas; 2012-2018 (6.5 years)

- Responsible for analysis and targeting to plan tactical operations for a Special Forces detachment.
- Liaison with Iraqi, Phillipine, Afghani, Korean, and Thai military partners to achieve mutual goals.

Special Forces Medical Sergeant (18D) Washington and overseas; 2007-2012 (5 years)

- Responsible for clinical and trauma care for special operations personnel on combat missions.
- Sole provider for medical services to indigenough people in Iraq, Afghanistan, and the Philippines.

Special Forces Trainee (18X)

North Carolina and Washington; 2004-2007 (2.5 years)

Education

M.S. Computer Science and Systems	University of Washington	December 2024
B.S. Software Engineering	Arizona State University	2022
China Exchange Program	Liaoning and Shenyang Universities, China	2018
Intensive Second Year Chinese Program	University of Washington	2013